<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Opinion on That Ferret Blog</title><link>https://thatferret.blog/tags/opinion/</link><description>Recent content in Opinion on That Ferret Blog</description><image><title>That Ferret Blog</title><url>https://thatferret.blog/images/thatferretblog-logo.png</url><link>https://thatferret.blog/images/thatferretblog-logo.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 15:55:30 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thatferret.blog/tags/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why we Don't Feed Whole Prey</title><link>https://thatferret.blog/posts/why-we-dont-feed-whole-prey/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 07:59:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thatferret.blog/posts/why-we-dont-feed-whole-prey/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post provides insight into whole prey feeding and why we don&amp;rsquo;t whole feed, which may benefit those considering different types of raw feeding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s not to say we disagree with whole prey feeding (I will outline some benefits as well). I am highlighting specific reasons we choose not to whole feed.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-whole-prey-feeding">What is whole prey feeding?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In short, whole prey feeding is where you feed whole prey to your ferrets — quite literally. It&amp;rsquo;s the entire carcass — including all the fluff!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why Ferrets Need Friends</title><link>https://thatferret.blog/posts/why-ferrets-need-friends/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 13:22:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thatferret.blog/posts/why-ferrets-need-friends/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ferrets are highly social animals and thrive with companionship. This post will explore why ferrets need friends and the benefits of having more than 1 ferret. It will also address lone ferrets.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="why-ferrets-need-other-ferrets">Why ferrets need other ferrets&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a common misconception that lone ferrets can &amp;lsquo;be fine&amp;rsquo; on their own, exceptional circumstances notwithstanding. All ferrets should be able to have other ferret friends. It&amp;rsquo;s important to keep ferrets in at least pairs or more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Where to Get a Ferret</title><link>https://thatferret.blog/posts/where-to-get-a-ferret/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 20:47:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thatferret.blog/posts/where-to-get-a-ferret/</guid><description>&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ve done the research, got everything on the checklist, and now you&amp;rsquo;re ready to get your ferrets! But where do you get them from?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When looking at getting ferrets there are basically 3 options.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Breeders&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pet Shops&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rescues/Shelters.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll dive into each option to help you decide where to get your ferrets.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="breeders">Breeders&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Ferrets from private and ethical Breeders will normally be younger ferrets (kits). They can be from accidental litters, bred for specific purposes (working or showing), bred as pets (for temperament and home life), or bred for specific markings, colours, or coats (the most common ones bred specifically for this purpose are Angora ferrets). The cost for bred ferrets varies drastically. The cost will depend on the specific breeders&amp;rsquo; fees and often the type and sex of the ferret. Costs can be from £50-£200 per ferret.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jack's Top Kitchen Picks</title><link>https://thatferret.blog/posts/jacks-top-kitchen-picks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 09:04:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thatferret.blog/posts/jacks-top-kitchen-picks/</guid><description>&lt;p>We spend plenty of time making food for our animals, raw food for our ferrets and our dog, and veg for our bearded dragons. That also means I frequently spend loads of time researching and using kitchen tools.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So here are my top picks for kitchen tools you should consider adding to your arsenal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All the links on this post are &lt;em>&lt;strong>not&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> affiliate links.&lt;br>
This &lt;em>may&lt;/em> change, and if so, will be fully disclosed.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>