<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Diet on That Ferret Blog</title><link>https://thatferret.blog/tags/diet/</link><description>Recent content in Diet on That Ferret Blog</description><image><title>That Ferret Blog</title><url>https://thatferret.blog/images/thatferretblog-logo.png</url><link>https://thatferret.blog/images/thatferretblog-logo.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 10:39:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thatferret.blog/tags/diet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why we Don't Feed Whole Prey</title><link>https://thatferret.blog/posts/why-we-dont-feed-whole-prey/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 07:59:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thatferret.blog/posts/why-we-dont-feed-whole-prey/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post provides insight into whole prey feeding and why we don&amp;rsquo;t whole feed, which may benefit those considering different types of raw feeding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s not to say we disagree with whole prey feeding (I will outline some benefits as well). I am highlighting specific reasons we choose not to whole feed.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-whole-prey-feeding">What is whole prey feeding?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In short, whole prey feeding is where you feed whole prey to your ferrets — quite literally. It&amp;rsquo;s the entire carcass — including all the fluff!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Raw Feeding 101</title><link>https://thatferret.blog/posts/raw-feeding-101/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 12:15:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thatferret.blog/posts/raw-feeding-101/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post will dive into raw feeding for ferrets. Raw 101 will be a series of posts on raw feeding (you can find all relevant posts on the series page). This is the main guide to all things raw and will include, kibble vs raw (condensed), ferret nutrition, types of diets and the amount of raw.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="why-raw-and-not-kibble">Why raw and not kibble?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Our blog will mainly discuss raw feeding as it is our preference, we have conducted much research on both raw feeding and kibble feeding to determine this. Raw food has many benefits for ferrets that kibble does not provide. These benefits include but are not limited to:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ferret Supplies &amp; Basics</title><link>https://thatferret.blog/posts/ferret-supplies-and-basics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 08:33:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thatferret.blog/posts/ferret-supplies-and-basics/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post will go more in-depth regarding ferret supplies! It will include supply ideas, where you can source supplies, DIY supplies, the cost of supplies, personal recommendations, and links. The linked supplies will be based in the UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All the links on this post are &lt;em>&lt;strong>not&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> affiliate links.&lt;br>
This &lt;em>may&lt;/em> change, and if so, will be fully disclosed.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="enclosurescages">Enclosures/Cages&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Ferrets need a lot of space. The more space you can offer, the better! Consider where your ferrets will live — maybe in their own room, sharing a living space with you, or being outside in the warmer months.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>