<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Behaviour on That Ferret Blog</title><link>https://thatferret.blog/tags/behaviour/</link><description>Recent content in Behaviour on That Ferret Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 14:17:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thatferret.blog/tags/behaviour/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why Ferrets Need Friends</title><link>https://thatferret.blog/posts/why-ferrets-need-friends/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 13:22:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thatferret.blog/posts/why-ferrets-need-friends/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ferrets are highly social animals and thrive with companionship. This post will explore why ferrets need friends and the benefits of having more than 1 ferret. It will also address lone ferrets.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="why-ferrets-need-other-ferrets">Why ferrets need other ferrets&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a common misconception that lone ferrets can &amp;lsquo;be fine&amp;rsquo; on their own, exceptional circumstances notwithstanding. All ferrets should be able to have other ferret friends. It&amp;rsquo;s important to keep ferrets in at least pairs or more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Basic Ferret Behaviours</title><link>https://thatferret.blog/posts/basic-ferret-behaviours/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 03:44:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thatferret.blog/posts/basic-ferret-behaviours/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ferrets display a wide variety of behaviours. From pouncing and digging to the famous &amp;lsquo;weasel war dance&amp;rsquo; this blog post will run through some of the most common ferret behaviours and why they do them!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have organised these behaviours into 8 separate categories.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="playful-behaviours">Playful Behaviours&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="war-dancing">War dancing&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Also referred to as the &amp;lsquo;weasel war dance&amp;rsquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s a series of jumps, hops, twists and dooking which normally result in invitations to play, chase or capture a toy. Ferrets will war dance at you or other ferrets, it&amp;rsquo;s a sign they&amp;rsquo;re very excited! In the wild, ferrets war dance to confuse their prey or other predatory species.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Basic Ferret Vocalisations</title><link>https://thatferret.blog/posts/basic-ferret-vocalisations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 03:34:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thatferret.blog/posts/basic-ferret-vocalisations/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ferrets make many noises, from happy dook-dooking to huffing. This blog post will highlight some common ferret sounds and their meanings!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="dooking">Dooking&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dooking is probably the most well-known ferret vocalisation. It often sounds like a soft and repetitive &amp;lsquo;clucking&amp;rsquo; sound, which can vary in pitch. Ferrets mostly dook when they&amp;rsquo;re happy. But there are actually multiple types of ferret dooking!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Such as:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Happy dooks. The most commonly known sound, ferrets will dook when feeling happy, playful or excited. Some ferrets don&amp;rsquo;t dook — this doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean they&amp;rsquo;re unhappy, it could just mean they were never taught how to dook!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>